all right hello Facebook and YouTube if
you are watching on the project's page
game B projects then you can join the
link in the comments if you would like
to participate on camera and tell us
what your project could have done if
it's not yet you know most of our
projects are in the beginning stages
they're not ready for use yes so it's
like what could it have done if it was
ready right now within this time of
quarantine and cope at 19 so who would
like to start answering the question the
question itself is how could my project
help in the pandemic yeah I could start
off so you know you can imagine when
when things were happening and this the
ants will be very similar dad riyals a
project of course because mine's kind of
a sub project of what he's doing but
there's a lot of kind of misinformation
like and I just had a friend hosting
today
why when we come out of this kind of
self isolation aren't we going to just
have the same thing would be better to
get sick now rather than later and are
we waiting for a cure why are we gonna
come out in two months when the Cure is
gonna be 18 months away and I think it'd
be nice to have a resource to where you
could have just that top question we
should self isolate and then it would
have all the reasons all the pros and
cons against it in there including like
you know so my friends were saying well
what about the economic impact and their
implication was I don't think it's worth
it I think we need to go and spend money
so that our economy doesn't crash he
didn't say that but I'm pretty sure
that's always thinking it would be nice
if he had some central place to go that
but instead I'm kind of like
regurgitating some of the things that I
thought you know that I heard and some
of my own thoughts and people were just
you know it's just a mix on this
Facebook message but if I had a link I
could just send them I'm sure there's a
lot of blog posts that kind of have
those but none of them currently have
that decision weighed with all the pros
and cons in a and an easy format to
explore so I think that and then a whole
bunch of the other things that if
as we were making these decisions we
could also have public input on it and
then have it displayed in a way the
decision displayed in a way that we can
actually see the pros and cons and the
relative weights that there would be a
lot less hopefully a lot less confusion
and even probably more people complying
with the suggestions like there's a
whole group of people that weren't
believing anything until someone from
their community got sick and was in the
hospital for weekend's like well okay
the facts you have are the same you know
why does it have to be you know so those
are the things that of course we're
trying trying to fix to where they don't
have to have a friend nearly die before
they start doing then a couple weeks
late doing what they should have been
doing in the first place because they
simply don't believe what they're being
told or well they believe the news
organization that's telling them the bad
things but anyways so that's kind of my
thoughts
all right because I can go next as
Bentley said yeah it was gonna be a lot
of overlap between the two
I mean it all comes down to people don't
know yes just sorry one second
Bentley didn't say the name of his
project it's recent score also Adriel
mention the name of your projects sounds
good thank you alright so Wicky lection
is the name of the project I wanted the
main sort of the the goal is stayed the
same or its to fight misinformation sort
of how I'm talking about it now is that
it sort of helps I guess establish a
point of trust is right now the average
person they don't really trust their
politicians they don't really trust
their new sources and even if you do
want to trust experts if there's ten
different experts saying ten different
things how do you know which expert to
trust so I mean there's a lot of sort of
different bits and pieces that wiki
election could help with one is sort of
acting as like a news aggregate so it's
taking all the different stories about
coronaviruses sort of lumpy them
together and then finding the stories
within that larger group to sort of
start getting down to okay here's you
know 20 stories that are all talking
about what's going on in Italy so if
you're now looking at any one of those
stories you could have something like a
browser extension that says hey you're
reading this story just so you know
here's sort of a higher level high roar
here's the the higher level story and
sort of what everyone agrees on here's
the thing people don't agree on and then
here's sort of what the experts who are
chiming and here's what they're saying
about that matter
and then also factoring in the the
experts so if you have ten experts that
aren't agreeing on things it's being
able to look at okay who's fully
qualified who's maybe actually made some
predictions in the past and they were
correct if certain politicians are
saying things you want to figure out
which ones are actually sort of
knowledgeable on this which one like to
give some sort of quantified answer to
who you can trust and why I think that's
probably the two main things it's just
acting as
source of information I got the news too
and then also I think that and this is
where a collection and recent scores
sort of overlap is trying to actually
figure out here's what all the experts
are saying here's the claims that are
being made and then here's which ones
actually have proof that's been reviewed
by qualified experts and you know where
the people who are actually qualified to
talk about this and have a history of it
what they're all saying yeah and I if
jublia wants to talk you can just let me
notably but I also want to kind of add
to that you do want to go ahead and say
yours sure I'll say mine nothing was
left right yeah I've had emergency I'm
like I can't even figure to restart this
thing um my project right now is
solution raising so I started the
Facebook group last week we just got
five under our belt and I'm now going
through them and we watch them so every
watched on we did on education the one
on food and this is all even though her
own advice was just starting and are in
our consciousness we mentioned it a few
times it's now basically we can't talk
about one without mentioning it but
every solution impacts this but even
more than that because of course just
like your projects those aren't done we
don't have 10,000 people at $100,000 but
having people locked in their houses
with nothing to do without hope and
without like how long is this gonna last
then what do I do what my rent having
something they can do a place they can
connect with and actually have
conversations that are generative so
they can see oh my goodness is possible
with a hundred thousand dollars right we
could have a food app we could be
pickles especially the food one I was
like we need to be growing in our
backyards right now like this needs to
be happening during this year now before
we have a how do we do without the
technology how do we do it without well
just sharing the knowledge and say with
the education we don't have childcare we
don't have our schools aren't going to
be back in till September at the
earliest probably so even though some
aren't quite admitting that yet now I
have my kid off for five months I was
worried about two months and it's weird
because now there's like this lifting of
anxiety run like yep and it for the long
haul like we got to figure it out it's
got to be something that can happen now
so I think during the pandemic solution
raising which is its own Facebook group
is
can focus on connecting people and
giving them hope and something to do
during this time of isolation yeah if I
can just build on that Jubilee I think
that's great I didn't even think about a
straight point that it's giving people
hope now so your project is is providing
value so I think that's fabulous and add
Rio for yours also have to think about
the kind of secondary effects that wiki
elections would provide because if that
was in place and if some of the news
organizations that were playing down the
pandemic and the earlier half I think
they would have been more cautious not
only what do people know not maybe not
to trust them but also I think they
would have been more accurate in their
reporting if they knew that there was
gonna be a record of what they were
saying and that people trusted that
record so that's that that's just
something I thought of when you were
talking I thought oh yeah that that that
has a real long-term effects right yeah
one of the visualization options that
like is gonna have to be in there is
some sort of a timeline where it's it's
taking all this content of like for
example the different administrations
and how seriously they were taking it
you can then take the videos and the
newspaper clippings and arrange them in
a timeline to say like here's the action
right here's the actual news and videos
and proof of how seriously they are
taking it at the different stages
because they're all you know a lot of
governments took a while to react and
then once they did made it sound like oh
we've been reacting the whole time but
we've been we know you weren't you were
saying it wasn't important it wasn't a
threat and now you're all of a sudden
saying it is which I think we all
expected all the government's to do that
but it's actually exactly having that
library of proof we're not anybody if
they want to verify it they can go check
a timeline and say no that rip right
there here's the 12 videos that you say
it's not important you know time stamp
and then the final ones I know it's
important I've been saying it's
important all along so we definitely
need some meaning sense making apps
right now something that helps doesn't
make sense of this because the
dis informations out there I feel like
the world is waking up to the fact our
governments are in no way a solution to
most of our problems yet they're the
best we have right now to coordinate and
all the grassroots things that are
happening that like it costs us to have
poor people in our society it costs us
to have people who don't have access to
information it costs us that we don't
trust the system and we can't just fix
that overnight we can't just be like
well now we can trust the news no we
can't trust our politicians we can't
trust the news I can't tell you the
number of times even now how many days
into it how many weeks into it that the
Canadian governments of the Canadian
media is like this many like now now
this this city has seen community
transmission like are you
kidding me of course there's community
transmission like this isn't this is way
past containment and we ran to the other
side so of course there's that's like
did you not think it was the same virus
as and these are elected officials and
sometimes medical personnel that are
like well now that we know it's
community transmitted in Vancouver now
that we know it's community transmitted
in Edmonton now we can start to self
isolate and it's like the first case
before the first case I mean our
northern provinces that have way less
medical care are taking this more
seriously when they don't even have a
case yet right maybe not more seriously
but seriously nonetheless we're not
waiting for cases they're not out having
Mardi Gras right now I was wondering
also maybe if we can think of any of the
other projects that have been shared and
project raisings
how we might think they might have
affected this as well even though
they're not represented here today
although I can't think of any oh yeah I
can cube spot if we had it up and
running right for local manufacturing
would definitely help with I mean and
with respirators with things we need
right now but also just like you don't
have that worry of like oh my goodness
this thing I really need it shipped over
from China where is it coming from and I
don't want me to just run them all off
or whether you want to talk about cubes
for a moment then go on to the next one
that's yeah I think hitting on that real
quick yeah I think if we could just if
every city or town had a three you know
it's more than 3d printing but could
print a medically viable
rest I'm sorry over they called Paris
they are called bridge okay which is you
know I don't know if you can just take a
garden hose and use that but yeah I
think there are certain parts like I
know I think it was in Italy people have
been 3d printing them and then the
medical that the company that makes
those has now been trying to sue them
yeah we've there's there's patent issues
in the US yeah as well they're talking
about suspending or not or whatever but
yeah yeah that she is gonna be one of
the more interesting parts of all this
is seeing sort of what companies come up
with any amount of goodwill on the other
side because if you're suing people for
printing respirator parts like you're
about to get lynched yeah absolutely
it's justifiably to like if you're
saying yeah I know that we kind of also
partially cause this but we're gonna
still need to make money off of saving
lives and even if they were like listen
we also may want to come out of this
other end as a company that's profitable
how can we help you in this and how can
we let say at the end I want 10 cents
per one or they don't be like something
that's like image so that we can also
yeah all that kind of stuff I think part
of the problem is that like they can't
even figure out how many that people are
making like they're completely out of
the loop and yeah it's been interesting
to see some companies actually being
like fairly good about things and like
giving their stuff for free and like
which you know is still big being done
from a business perspective but at least
they're trying to keep everything in
context and then some companies just
really don't care and they don't even
want like one day of loss profit
I was critical of Disney yesterday
because they had seven days of free
Disney Plus and I was like everyone else
is giving 30 days because you know
they're gonna be addicted at the end and
they still need it you're still inside
right but it was like also Disney just
lost all of their streams of profit all
of their resorts all of their so I was
like okay maybe one of their students of
profit which probably isn't even their
their most profitable people aren't
gonna be buying you don't need me Mickey
Mouse anything whether online or a box
store or like this is just not like I'm
like I get it they're one thing but
still could you not have enough to give
away 30 days because then your
kids at home first five months you're
still gonna be streaming Disney if you
could afford it anywhere I think is
Abigail Disney she's a CEO or she just
like a sheer whole time
okay because she came out and like
called out Disney because when they shut
down I think it was the world they had
like this epic fireworks celebration it
was like this massive crowd she's like
are you kidding me she like was
on record as saying that like to
newspapers I think like she tweeted at
them or something like yeah I think
she's either the CEO or like she's a
major shareholder or something like
she's the guy's daughter or niece or
granddaughter or something but yeah I
think we're gonna see all of the ways
that that like I said trust it's not
just about my trust it's about if you
trust the media it's but if you trust
the government and that costs me
something it costs everyone something
because how do we trust what they're
saying when one week it's like we're
fine just keep your distance maybe a
little bit and you can have 250 people
gatherings but at the same time we're
saying that you shouldn't be having play
dates like it's like one or the other
like what are we doing you're having a
way it makes sense that and why what is
the math what is the 250 pieces person
reasoning because then you have 250
people infected by a cough as opposed to
two people who then transmit it and
transmit it and and figuring that out so
yeah no cube spawn would be a great one
to have um I guess digital native I
can't read lots the education vignette
that would be having something that is
is able to access education or any of
the solutions we came up with renard
education solution raising yeah people
working on that education issues right
now a lot of teachers are fumbling
around trying to figure out how to get
their courses online and teach kids
while they're there kid you know the
younger kid is in the background and
they're trying to take care of their kid
and stuff like that I was yeah I was
thinking today it'd be so nice to have a
full online curriculum that anyone could
use and you could just kind of jump into
and then have you know video it's a
thing some of the stuff we talked about
we'd have tutors I could come on and
tutor two or three people at a time or a
group of five or whatever
should I see that there is an app to
like a sign homework and stuff in China
and the kids review bombed up weird one
stars to get out the a fixture to get it
off the App Store so that they couldn't
go Chinese kids moderate problems with
very modern solutions like I could just
down vote this brilliant like they just
got together like I don't feel like
doing homework what are the other things
that we've not done a project raising on
but I have talked about them and they're
in the game be space Harris and Colleen
their project and I'm gonna butcher the
name Shankar Anka something where it's
the online and they're out of Utah so
it's like an online farmers market that
gets the food from the farmers and then
distributes it to people and they have
trouble they don't have trouble bringing
in farmers they have trouble bringing in
the people like don't think you look
great and the people right now and they
have it in a way that it can be
franchised in every city and having that
available now would be awesome but I
also think we need to be coordinating
with our farmers to make sure they have
enough labor to get the food out of the
fields so that when it's ready no not
preemptively but like so that because
especially in Canada we're not bringing
in immigrant workers we're not bringing
our migrant workers that we do every
single years because they work for cheap
so that what who's gonna pick all that
food and there's people looking for jobs
right and people looking for something
to do so I think a online farmers market
especially since like I said there's
this franchisable and I don't you think
they charge for it it's just like an
open source software here's the process
call the farmers call the cool and now
have this this set up is would like I
was like I don't have the energy to do
that in Vancouver but I'm like I really
would like to eat in six months
someone's got to take this on and beg
dinner and every different city and we
have farmers so how do we actually
actually coordinate this and how do we
get the labor piece in there to because
now they're gonna need drivers and you
have to deal with things on a different
level like even the community kitchens I
was like can you have committee kitchens
I don't know but yeah that's the top I
can't think of any of
other ones that I'm sure every single
one has a possibility in yeah in the
game be space there's a lot of
discussions about ubi and other
financial models which of course you
know if we weren't tied to having to
work for many of us an hour or you know
a paycheck to in order to justify living
that would kind of easy a few things you
know my my son was laid off and then
we're gonna have to lay off the health
care worker that helps by mom so it's
just a chain reaction because he lives
with her and pays half the rent and so
she can no longer if he's not paying
rent she can't afford her helper and
then you know it's a lot of people are
going to be struggling so some of the a
lot of the the concepts about different
ways of categorizing work and you know
what what what oh you have to provide an
initial income I think would be would
help in situations like this as well
yeah and making sure I mean that small
businesses make it through to the other
end because so many small businesses are
going bankrupt and they're not able to
pay their employees and they're put like
and so there's no job to come back to on
the other end and those services are
gonna be provided and so having a ubi
for the employees means and and just to
pause a pause on the payments right
because then you can say okay even if I
am a business owner and I can't make the
money I don't have to pay my staff I
don't have to pay my lease I don't have
to buy new stuff and then I can figure
out how to get myself fed because I get
ubi and then we can unpause the economy
in you know six months to a year I mean
I'd love ubi and I love debt Jubilee but
like I don't think we can ubi we can do
but the dead Jubilee has a lot of
implications that we won't necessarily
know and while people are in their
houses is not the time for revolution
that involves going down the street like
we need people to be rational and calm
as they can be in this in this difficult
time and ubi would help immensely with
that as well as forgiving
the big payments like rent and mortgage
yeah a lot of those solutions do have a
lot of economic risks that need to be
figured out so I'm not saying we need to
jump in any of those right away but as
we continue to work on those ideas I'm
sure that they'll offer some fruits that
the next time this happens and there
will be a next time and or most likely
be worse we'll be better prepared
hopefully yeah and with a lot of that
there there does seem to be some
hesitancy around like well we don't want
to do anything you know this we don't
want what a rush you're like well if you
don't rush you're still gonna have a
bunch of big problems like in the US
especially when that that cascading
effect is way worse than in a lot of the
countries that have universal health
care and that kind of thing like our
sister very well might lose her business
which there's like over 50 jobs gone I
think sure he did well yeah I've been
talking to her in it yeah it seems quite
quite likely which and you know she's by
far not the only one like she was
working with we had the company
specializes in brick and mortar
basically any brick and mortar business
that's not a grocery store is hurting
right now
like sometimes they're already under
yeah we're thinking about contacting
some of the local restaurants we go to
and see if they're doing the takeout or
not rolling the homegrown ones but then
I don't know maybe I should be ordering
doordash from Wendy's which is which I
got to about once or twice a week even
though they're larger corporation
they're gonna need it as well so trying
to make those decisions yeah that's the
hard part is deciding like which
corporations to try to help even if you
don't really like the corporation which
is like the restaurant well we were I
was like I said I was we watching the
solution on food and you're your
solution Adriel for using like door -
but having it more scheduled so you know
you're getting one at 6:00 p.m. this
would be an amazing time for that
because they don't have walk-in
customers so knowing I'm gonna make
fifty pad ties like bringing the cost
down knowing that also listen if you're
sick don't make hard food and we'll
figure it out right let me hear will you
recover to buy it to do that but right
now not or we can have workers come in
or like no you're sick no other people
will come in and you'll still get your
you paid for you'll still get you don't
mean that the restaurants know that
they're good at you
and as Ernesto just said like the
delivery people are a definite a risk
factor but that ultra means if you're
running a company properly and it's not
purely profit based you can then take
that extra step and say hey this is our
best choice because it's either that or
people hopper go out constantly so we're
gonna make sure that our delivery people
are like super cautious and like you
know where whatever said we decide that
we need to take in order to make sure
that it's safe from kitchen to delivery
to handoff we can make that you know I
wouldn't call it a high risk contagion
factor because it's less than going to a
store and it's less than going out and
sitting in a restaurant it's still less
and we got a real it higher in just the
fact that like they do here they're
delivering the contagion to you so if a
delivery person has it they can in fact
fifty people all dotted across a map
yeah but it I mean with this specific
disease maybe not the other ones it
would be hard and a single door handoff
to in fact someone else because unless
there's actually some fluid on the
delivery box I mean so like you know if
they're delivering in a bag and you take
down the bag it's more of the cooks that
would give it to you than the delivery
person but you know you've got to get
food anyways I guess also though we
probably shouldn't rely too much on the
information itself the experts okay like
they were saying from four weeks that it
wasn't airborne on another like Oh turns
out it probably is well that's there's a
lot of confusion there because it is not
airborne but when they say airborne they
mean technically it does not flow
through the air on its own but to me if
someone coughs and it goes six feet away
that's airborne well so that's they're
using a technical term and they're
misleading people and that's wrong
things that reason scored point out is
he shouldn't go out in public say it's
not an airborne disease because when you
say that the person to me that you know
an airplane is airborne it is it plus I
think that we're designing to handle
this yeah we can't only design it for
the coronavirus or or go ahead nineteen
right things already
or that we need to make sure that like
okay because it's a different risk
factor but like there's the cooks
there's the ability people there's like
if your ability person how do you make
sure that you're at no risk of getting
contaminated from the person you're
delivering to right and there's sort of
all those and you know maybe that's just
a system that you design and it you know
goes in the back and then when we say
all right it's go time
enable it train people on it make sure
that you verified that they all
understand what their responsibilities
are a no-go well I think they're also
like you the delivery person you don't
get cash right you have to pay by credit
card just gonna vote people who don't
have cash options but having you they
leave it outside your door right in a
text saying hey go get it so they're not
coming in contact with you or your money
and so therefore they're gonna have a
much they're only gonna have the risk
factor of the restaurant if the
restaurants doing 40 meals all at once
you know it's a delivered at six if it's
called sorry these are weird times like
right you're getting it at six in your
neighborhood so here's how many are
getting dropped off and dropping them
off in order and it's it's just it's a
different delivery method and if we're
not if we have ubi people aren't just
desperate to need to be a driver so
they're not going to show up sick it's
actually more of a service they're
giving to get a little extra money and
same with the cooks and everyone else
right that it's like okay if you can be
sick and still get paid therefore you
can spend the time off and we can all be
healthier and then we can design systems
that are more about keeping the
contagion as safe as possible and then
when there's that something happens
right you find out that your delivery
did give you something then you can give
that information back in the system and
it isn't about bankrupting that
restaurant because they were horrible
it's like how do we get that information
on so everyone knows that they had it
maybe they might need to self quarantine
more than just socially isolate and
following that not around right to say
right if you're a cook and you come in
and you're perfectly fine you pass it on
to someone it's not really your fault
you know you were trying to do good and
to to the points that one is we are all
getting it's just the speed that we get
it so the fact that delivery people are
deployed that's actually part of the
feature and also there will be people
that die because the economic
well we don't order from these companies
people will die that way - so you know I
we do we do want the right now maybe not
in future outbreaks but we do want it to
slowly spread through for now there
might be better ideas but the current
plan is let it slowly spread so to have
delivery workers just slowly spreading
it a little bit isn't horrible it's not
nice but but Nestor doesn't want to
happen you just said that he'd quit 15
days ago because of all the the the
higher the higher risk of going into
apartment buildings and that's part of
it is is working with the delivery
people and working with the the system
to say how do we make you as safe as
possible what could have been in place
you would still be there maybe we don't
deliver to apartment buildings or you
don't do signing for things right
like freak the credit credit card famous
right like we're no longer psy.d and you
have to do it online that's good enough
we're in a different time in China one
of the reasons you're looking is they
all just have their QR CS on the phone
that's how they pay for everything so in
every store it was like scan this scan
this scan this and so there was no
touching either away whereas here you
have cashiers with plastic gloves on but
they're handing you back and they're
doing all this other stuff and they're
touching your credit card and they're
doing it's like that's not it I don't
want to get sick but you all share the
diseases and bacteria of everyone that
I've helped today yeah and in the u.s.
we start to sign for our credit cards
and so everyone's touched that same pin
exactly I need to start carrying a pen
even if it means like door - no no a lot
of him you don't but there's some some
some of the restaurants so I guess yeah
not for door okay well I was just
wondering cuz I still mentioned people
signing and I was like I mean it might
be a different kind of it yeah I don't
know Ernesto where you're I don't
remember where Ernest is I think I think
what is in place would probably need to
be designed around some sort of a you
have an account you know you tell us
like your address your all the stuff and
then you would get charged and possibly
even you might be able you know to mail
in a check or something and then you
cash it okay you know have 200 ORS of
credit or there's options but it would
be about minimizing
especially during things like this this
is one of them I think it did come up Oh
turn our disease one which I haven't
list free listen to but talking about
having smart health devices and there's
one that already exists I mean there's
money that already exists but one is a
digital thermometer and so the company
that gets the information back to them
actually has a like a map of the United
States why it's all in the United States
I don't know that shows like they could
they can say it a pandemics are saying
epidemics coming before other people can
see it because they can see people the
raising temperature in certain areas
right that there's a lot of people here
who have it and Florida is red right now
the rest of the stage is Orange Florida
is red right now which makes sense
because everyone went there for Spring
Break with all the old people and now
they're gonna bring it everywhere back
to the jig because it was there fu to
the system yeah and yeah their
government seems particularly resistant
to wanting to do something about this
like I know all the stories up and
reading or like all these states locking
down in Florida be like we're not
locking down we're gonna have a beach
party but no more than 15 people we're
back in to trust their son what's safe
and what's not there you go he was
working for a pizza place and oh yeah
yeah so changing some of how we handle
signatures and cash and things would
probably help with that situation so
next time I just had a weird thought I
wonder if people are gonna freak out so
much more change our processes to where
we don't share as many germs and there
are some benefits to your the standard
person's immune system being exposed to
small amounts so hopefully don't go the
other way but I don't know it was
interesting I went to go pick up a
package from UPS yesterday and just this
shift in like okay card down there okay
put this down it was all like trying to
minimize purchasing anything and it
seemed like I understood why he was
doing it of course but it just seems so
like weird to go through like this like
very standoffish like you stand there
put your car down I'll look at it and
then like put your slip down I'll write
the number on it was start to have those
glass shields like they used to happen
yeah and then maybe an info UV lights
everywhere yeah which if that becomes a
permanent thing I have the same concerns
you bet me like is that too far now cuz
you kind of need some germs like those
of us who aren't concerned about dying
from it itself that's actually good for
us like to go and to get sick and to get
exposed and to get kind of quasi sick
for a day be like oh I just bought
something off I do feel and this is I in
no way want to not flatten the curve but
to actually take healthy people that
know that there are 99% not gonna have
risk from it put them in like do the
opposite of what other people and like
not let go about your life in this
contagion everyone but like you get
exposed to it you get it but your
contain and then two weeks later your
hopefully immune you can go about having
the economy work right like and you're
like especially those people who are
healthy but are scared about their
finances to be like hey you're gonna
make some big bank if you're immune if
you're immune we don't know yet but
creating it in but that's a whole other
that's the emergency workers like if you
know if all of a sudden a whole bunch of
people from like a grocery store get
sick oh crap now what like they can't
shut down I think in two states they'd
they just classify grocery workers as as
emergency support workers like yeah that
that's that's interesting Ernesto
mentioned that they were letting them
stay open so that they can sell their
inventory so that's yeah that's about a
risk balance sort of decision which you
know yeah I may be kind of disagree with
but it's hard I'm interested to see if
he feels that he can't quantify it
Ernesto on a scale of one to ten how
much do you feel that the people in
Florida trust the politicians at the
state level like ten being the most
so do you think some hand lotion is
gonna skyrocket that's what the stock
price is I'm gonna yeah I went shopping
for the first time you know like the
last two three weeks yesterday and like
I probably checked five stores no
sanitizer no toilet paper
very little hand soap lotion for your
house my hands are horrible right now
because of how often I've been and you
see how often I touch my face so yeah I
can't that too like I'm like I'm 40 and
I have not managed to not like bite my
nails or not touch my face or not I'm
like this is not the time then that's
gonna happen I'm trying this is life or
death for some of my family members and
I'm like and I can't do it so it shows
that it's not there's a video fooling
around of some woman who was giving some
talkin to be doing and it was like 20
things in a row of like her going to
know and then her oh no it was just like
two minutes of just her stopping
yourself and touching your face and just
the cost of doing that it was yes I was
thinking we need a little q-tip and the
sleeve that you just pull out do your
back in so it's maybe even has a little
alcohol in there I do think red things
isn't necessarily an idea that we could
implement right but we could also oh
there we go 9 out of 10 people wanted
most things closed but the 10% are doing
the complete opposite
just to show self-determination oh my
god we don't believe you gotta trust you
it's like we're gonna gather in these
big groups in same with in Ontario which
was BC was actually catching up and
surpassing because they were doing
things then like their colleges had st.
Patrick's Day celebrations BC we've been
taking it pretty seriously like our
government's actually been talking about
stuff and shutting things down and doing
some stuff like they probably could have
done more but overall it's been not
horrible not as bad as some other places
but um common common planets plan for
their currency of being based
it's kind of as dangerous as the debt
Jubilee we're like okay but it could be
something that starts with the
grassroots and says hey no we don't have
that option they're not giving us ubi so
we're gonna make our own cryptocurrency
if it's based on doing the labor and X
amount per day right it's are you bi
plus hey you get delivery you get X
amount of money for that and now we need
to be able to distribute the food but
we'd have to be able to create the food
too so I don't think the farmers going
to come in and be a part of it yeah ubi
method and they can make Bank on that on
the outside yeah yeah that's what's
comment about over and left should be
stopped which is interesting because if
they're saying don't take public transit
which completely makes sense because one
person does it you can affect a bunch
but then an uber and left it's like if
you take away both I mean I guess that
kind of helps enforce the quarantine
like what you can't go anywhere because
there's no bus doesn't know over and no
left just also there's there's people
who need to get to the hospital in
ambulances and ambulances won't pick
them up because they can't like
quarantine it right which is like it's
so they like you drive they're like what
if you don't can't drive what do you
take public transit call a taxi like
what is your option isn't the ambulance
the option in that case like yeah I mean
you almost need like maybe a subset of
your ambulances to be like all right
these are the ones that we're pretty
sure are infected even then we'll still
do our best to clean them but like you
should only go to pick up people for
coronavirus if we're picking up somebody
for a respiratory issue don't send one
of these yeah yeah exactly you should
have green yellow and red
these ones are clean no one had it and
they should still be disinfected every
time in case they did have it you know
which you don't know also goes to the
scary part of what he used to disinfect
because are we just creating the next
super bug right now with everyone
slathering on the all the the sanitizer
you know that kills 99.99% of bacteria
you end up with some really strong point
zero zero one percent of bacteria yeah I
think they're mostly back to alcohols so
instead of using the antibacterial but
this Oh does that not have the same
issue
oh and no they there's no they can't
develop an immunity to the whole mess
okay that's more of a physical okay it's
howhow soap dissolves the the fat layer
okay yeah yeah interesting that's good
yes but we also I mean I don't think
that the virus is a bacteria will evolve
to not die from soap but there are other
things we do that are absolute like the
antibacterial stuff that or the sprays I
don't know what they're using for the
sprays whether they do get the more we
try to combat it like that but there's
no other choice right now I mean that's
kind of the best of the best we have and
we don't have a vaccine and we don't
have treatment options that will that
will kill it and so yes there any other
of the people who come on Project
raisings
I mean I know there are trying to think
there's the how to do it there was the
guy who was trying to come up with like
I think the models were had a build like
the things like animals survive more in
these cities I don't think that's
particularly applicable to this just cuz
it's more right right right with the 3d
modeling yeah 3d sorry I'm like using
sort of common stuff right a PVC pipe
and pop bottles and stuff like that to
sort of create these structures to help
I think it was although I think his was
part animals and I think there was a bit
of like urban gardening so the urban
gardening part could be useful and it's
been very interesting to see how when
the humans run around animals have just
been taken over there was like the gangs
of monkeys in Thailand there was a thing
in I think was India where the the
farmers were you know being quarantined
and so some elephants broke into a
winery and ate their grapes and drank
some of their wine and passed out
interesting
all right let's see here we have you we
have wiki lection we have all been home
which is what you were talking about
with the project brainstorming
brainstorming like add up the help cube
spawn kind act with yonus which is
similar to your guys's project and again
then brainstorming brainstorming so I
mean we haven't actually had that many
of them which reminds me we're supposed
to kind of have one tomorrow but we
don't have anyone set up for one and
what do we want to do you could do a
project raising specifically on
good on my brain sorry I'm brainstorming
what could we do drew like kind of like
a solution raising but not quite a
solution raising on what could happen
during the pandemic what could we come
together and do um or yeah what do you
want to do tomorrow so I'm not sure if
this is interesting one of the things
that I've sort of shifted a bit of
direction with the whole quarantine
thing is I'm now drawing up some plans
for like the actual early aspects for
quick election I don't be paying out of
pocket like the first version to to be
coded during all this I'm also planning
like the first step to be a app that we
can branch and create wiki election on a
part of it but then also create the
together attack like the list of
projects and the work done and and then
hopefully I don't know if there's
anything around like sort of deciding
what the MVP might look like more on
like the together tech side like what
what do we feel would be useful if we
can actually get people to start using
what do we think is maybe a more
important feature during the whole
quarantine like to actually sort of plan
out what would the first version of a
together tech app what should it be able
to do what do we think especially right
now people being at home and maybe not
having work to do especially if you were
laid off but still want to do stuff what
that part of it might look like so do we
want to do a project raising on together
tech will lead to both the people who
the project and the people talking about
it but like I think we're good at that
yeah to do together tech up figure out
an MVP for together tech yeah which is a
bit unique is we haven't really they've
done like any MVP actual David right
like what what do they need but that
might be like the next evolution in the
project raising is you have a solution
raising of a project raising and then
there's like the next step words I've
actually kind of started something or
I'm about to start something in the
actual rubber hit the road
mm-hm doing stuff so you know just
someone see the scheduler that they
tagged us all on wanna citizens
Marsyas yeah I haven't seen what he what
he ended up building yeah I saw some of
these screenshots I haven't looked too
far into it cuz I'm not that into life
that part of the scheduling I won't want
these guys willing like for the project
side which is sort of part of it but
that will branch off into this theater
Tech and whatever you make for the topic
based thing I'm gonna see if I can use
it for the solution raisins which oh I
don't know they're not like to say
solutionizing then just put in brackets
that will be recording it right like
it'll be live or alive and recorded like
it's not which next probably would be a
flag on the meeting that you're
suggesting I'm suggesting a noon one
oh and I want to record these as an
ongoing thing so if you say you want
participate be aware of that absolutely
I'm gonna play well I only just saw it
he only puts it like two hours golly
just saw it like 45 minutes ago like I'm
in a different state I can't read
through this but it looks awesome mm-hmm
yeah it's night like I definitely took
note like oh damn we have actually have
a coder coding stuff now cool that is
very cool which is part of the thing
that sort of made me start just be IDs
what we're gonna do tomorrow then it's
talk about an MVP for the meta project
together attack because we should
probably put up a thing we should not we
probably we were are going to put up a
thing on the solution on the project's
page the game view projects page for
this is the time it's a 9 a.m. right
tomorrow's is it 90 I'm not the 2 p.m.
one which will be 10 a.m. my time but
that's like a different time zone at the
moment it's so hard cuz my computer's at
my normal at Vancouver and I keep like
doing the wrong chain time changed in my
head but in any way I was half an hour
late so they gave me coffee house how
could yesterday day before yesterday
because of that but not the point yeah
so writing up what it is for doing and
then putting up do you want to give any
drugs I think you'll be able to
communicate what it is we're actually
doing it at MVP and the meta project
better
I'm sure yeah oh yeah that Timaeus
little awkward yet
switched into a project meeting IRA for
reading a little bit here but that's
fine I think we talked about our
projects when they can do in the
pandemic and then do you mean why wait
till next week the world's happening so
rapidly are you frozen
I saw you blink we need to organize the
YouTube page the YouTube like actually
make it look slightly more professional
with a banner and a logo and a more also
broken down into solution raising
project raising that I don't have access
to actual YouTube and plus doing the
crip shins and adding stuff and doing
and doing that if I can get access to
your YouTube channel our YouTube channel
but you're the one who created it if
there is like a user password I can no
see if you can send me the username that
you use on there I'll see if I imagine
there's probably some ability to add
moderators and stuff like that I'd be
shocked ok yeah there probably is
alright it's like a lot of the big like
even just youtubers they have a full
team behind them that does stuff so I
would have think it's true episode this
it's all bad that issue they're so dry
maybe that's good that's the source it's
like nothing could even live on them
there's like a desert that's the whole
plan yeah but I had that bad cuz I mean
I wash my hands like whatnot you know
I'm about to go outside or when I come
back do it that often so hey we're all
all pretty tired from what's going on in
the world should be say goodbye to
YouTube and Facebook and call it
slightly short all right I'll see you
guys see people tomorrow morning for the
project raising and I just let everyone
know this is our new time we're doing
the Friday ones at noon pacific standard
time not 11 a.m. and hour later than it
was before
or our schedules alright